

JONNE AALTO

Product & Team builder

+358466321564



jonne.aalto@gmail.com

https://aaltjo798.github.io/Portfolio/

EDUCATION

Specialist Qualification

Management and Business Administration Business College Helsinki

SKILLS

- Team lead
- Programming
- **UI** Design
- Sales
- **Business development**
- Deep research
- AI/LLM/RAG/Agents

LANGUAGE

- English
- Finnish

PROFILE

I'm a 24-year-old product and team builder from Finland. Currently working as an IT consultant and building a few products on the side. I have experience in startups, operations, and business development, and lately I've been helping companies explore practical use cases for LLMs and agent-based AI tools.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Solotech TMI

2024 - current

IT Consultant

- Currently building a PRD and Figma prototype for a web
- Made deep market research and cash flow forecast for the business

Lahjakamu Oy

2023 - 2024

COO

- Built an awesome team and kept the core focused and on
- Build a Figma prototype of 2 different large-scale web applications
- Made a massive partner collaboration

Voltaco Oy

2022- 2023

Co-Founder / Operations

- Made the company's first 10k and got the first client.
- Made business plans and opened the core supply chanells

Tehomen Oy

2019-2022

Elecrtic charging specialist

- Installed over 1000 electric charging stations
- · Mapping, installation and maintence